[
    {
        "question": "1. What do you mean by replication?",
        "answer": "In replication, data is synchronized between two or more servers. This is a method of storing the same data on more than one site or server. This feature allows data to be accessed seamlessly even during server downtimes or heavy traffic. Users gain consistent access to data while not interfering with or slowing down those of other users.   Replication of data is more than just a backup. A publisher is considered to be the server that originates the data, and a subscriber is the one where it is replicated. Data replication involves the publisher synchronizing its transaction with the subscriber and updating subscriber data automatically. A change made on the publisher's side is automatically reflected on the subscriber's side as well.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What do you mean by BLE (Bluetooth Low Energy)?",
        "answer": "Beginners may see BLE (Bluetooth Low Energy) as a type of Bluetooth that uses less power, uses less energy. BLE, or Bluetooth Smart, is a relatively new form of Bluetooth technology that consumes much less power and costs than classic Bluetooth while offering a similar range of communication. As shown in the following diagram, BLE is not a replacement for Classic Bluetooth and they both serve a specific marketplace.   The Bluetooth Low Energy technology has been developed with the purpose of facilitating the IoT. Generally, the Internet of Things is about connecting devices with each other, usually via a wireless connection, such as Bluetooth low energy to allow them to communicate and share data. With its high energy efficiency, BLE has become a preferred and ideal choice for IoT. IoT enthusiasts and application developers have increasingly adopted Bluetooth LE to connect smart devices.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What are the different components of IoT?",
        "answer": "IoT devices usually consist of four main components as follows:   Sensors: A sensor or device is an important component for gathering live data from the surrounding environment. The nature of this data can vary. This could be as simple as your phone having a temperature sensor, GPS, an accelerometer, or as complex as a live video feature on a social media platform. Sensors make it possible for IoT devices to connect to the real world and environment.\nConnectivity: Upon collection, all data is sent to a cloud infrastructure. This could be done by connecting the sensors to the cloud using a variety of communication mediums such as mobile or satellite networks, Bluetooth, WI-FI, WAN, etc. Various IoT devices use different types of connectivity.\nData Processing: Once the data has been collected, and has reached the cloud, it is the responsibility of the data processors to process it. Data processing software can enhance IoT devices in a wide range of ways, from adjusting the temperature of the air conditioner to recognizing faces on mobile phones.\nUser Interface: An IoT device interacts with a user through a User Interface. A user interface is the visible, tangible component of an IoT system that can be accessed by users. It involves presenting the information in a way that is valuable to the end-user. A well-designed user interface will simplify the experience for users and encourage them to interact more. Information needs to be made accessible to end-users in some way, like sending them alerts via notification, email or text message. Sensors: A sensor or device is an important component for gathering live data from the surrounding environment. The nature of this data can vary. This could be as simple as your phone having a temperature sensor, GPS, an accelerometer, or as complex as a live video feature on a social media platform. Sensors make it possible for IoT devices to connect to the real world and environment. Sensors: Connectivity: Upon collection, all data is sent to a cloud infrastructure. This could be done by connecting the sensors to the cloud using a variety of communication mediums such as mobile or satellite networks, Bluetooth, WI-FI, WAN, etc. Various IoT devices use different types of connectivity. Connectivity: Data Processing: Once the data has been collected, and has reached the cloud, it is the responsibility of the data processors to process it. Data processing software can enhance IoT devices in a wide range of ways, from adjusting the temperature of the air conditioner to recognizing faces on mobile phones. Data Processing: User Interface: An IoT device interacts with a user through a User Interface. A user interface is the visible, tangible component of an IoT system that can be accessed by users. It involves presenting the information in a way that is valuable to the end-user. A well-designed user interface will simplify the experience for users and encourage them to interact more. Information needs to be made accessible to end-users in some way, like sending them alerts via notification, email or text message. User Interface:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What are the advantages of IoT?",
        "answer": "An IoT (Internet of Things) system is an advanced automation and analytics system that makes use of networking, big data, sensing, and Artificial Intelligence to provide a complete solution. It provides the following benefits:   Improved customer engagement: IoT facilitates a better customer experience by automating tasks. In a car, for instance, any issue will be detected automatically by sensors. It will be notified to both the driver and manufacturer.\nTechnical optimization: IoT has improved technology and made it more efficient. It has turned even old \"dumb\" devices into \"smart\" ones by making them able to transmit data over the internet, facilitating communication with people and other IoT-enabled devices. For example, coffee machines, smart toys, smart microwaves, etc.\nEase of Access: IoT has now enabled access to real-time information from (almost) any location. All you need is a smart device connected to the internet.\nImproved Insights: Currently we rely on superficial insights to make decisions, but IoT provides real-time insights that lead to more efficient resource management.\nNew business opportunities: By collecting and analyzing data from the network, you can uncover new business insights and generate new opportunities while reducing operational costs.\nEffective Time Management: Overall, the Internet of Things can save you a lot of time. While we commute to work, we can read the latest news on our phones, browse a blog about our favourite hobby, or shop online.\nImproved security measures: Using IoT, access control systems can provide additional security to organizations and individuals. As an example, IoT technology in surveillance can assist in improving security standards in an organization, as well as identifying any suspicious activity. Improved customer engagement: IoT facilitates a better customer experience by automating tasks. In a car, for instance, any issue will be detected automatically by sensors. It will be notified to both the driver and manufacturer. Improved customer engagement: Technical optimization: IoT has improved technology and made it more efficient. It has turned even old \"dumb\" devices into \"smart\" ones by making them able to transmit data over the internet, facilitating communication with people and other IoT-enabled devices. For example, coffee machines, smart toys, smart microwaves, etc. Technical optimization: Ease of Access: IoT has now enabled access to real-time information from (almost) any location. All you need is a smart device connected to the internet. Ease of Access: Improved Insights: Currently we rely on superficial insights to make decisions, but IoT provides real-time insights that lead to more efficient resource management. Improved Insights: New business opportunities: By collecting and analyzing data from the network, you can uncover new business insights and generate new opportunities while reducing operational costs. New business opportunities: Effective Time Management: Overall, the Internet of Things can save you a lot of time. While we commute to work, we can read the latest news on our phones, browse a blog about our favourite hobby, or shop online. Effective Time Management Improved security measures: Using IoT, access control systems can provide additional security to organizations and individuals. As an example, IoT technology in surveillance can assist in improving security standards in an organization, as well as identifying any suspicious activity. Improved security measures:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What are the challenges or risks associated with IoT?",
        "answer": "The following are some security risks associated with IoT:   Privacy: Connected IoT devices are vulnerable to hacking. Many IoT devices collect and transmit personal data over an open network without encryption, making it easy for hackers to access. Hackers may also use cloud endpoints to attack servers.\nInsufficient testing & Outdated product: In a fast-paced market like IoT, many companies or manufacturers rush to start releasing their products and software without doing enough testing. Many of them don't provide timely updates as well. Unlike other devices such as smartphones, IoT devices are not updated, which can leave them vulnerable to data theft. Thus, IoT devices should be tested thoroughly and updated as soon as new vulnerabilities are identified in order to maintain security.\nLack of knowledge and awareness: Despite being a growing technology, people do not know much about IoT. A major security threat associated with IoT is the user's lack of knowledge and awareness of its capabilities. This poses a threat to all users.\nNetwork Connectivity: Network connectivity can be challenging for many IoT devices. Particularly if such devices are widely dispersed, in remote locations, or if bandwidth is severely limited.\nReliability: Given the highly distributed nature of IoT devices, it can be difficult to ensure the reliability of IoT systems. Various conditions can affect the components that make up an IoT system, such as natural disasters, disruptions in cloud services, power outages, and system failures. Privacy: Connected IoT devices are vulnerable to hacking. Many IoT devices collect and transmit personal data over an open network without encryption, making it easy for hackers to access. Hackers may also use cloud endpoints to attack servers. Privacy: Insufficient testing & Outdated product: In a fast-paced market like IoT, many companies or manufacturers rush to start releasing their products and software without doing enough testing. Many of them don't provide timely updates as well. Unlike other devices such as smartphones, IoT devices are not updated, which can leave them vulnerable to data theft. Thus, IoT devices should be tested thoroughly and updated as soon as new vulnerabilities are identified in order to maintain security. Insufficient testing & Outdated product: Lack of knowledge and awareness: Despite being a growing technology, people do not know much about IoT. A major security threat associated with IoT is the user's lack of knowledge and awareness of its capabilities. This poses a threat to all users. Lack of knowledge and awareness: Network Connectivity: Network connectivity can be challenging for many IoT devices. Particularly if such devices are widely dispersed, in remote locations, or if bandwidth is severely limited. Network Connectivity: Reliability: Given the highly distributed nature of IoT devices, it can be difficult to ensure the reliability of IoT systems. Various conditions can affect the components that make up an IoT system, such as natural disasters, disruptions in cloud services, power outages, and system failures. Reliability:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. What are different types of sensors in IoT?",
        "answer": "In recent years, Internet-of-Thing sensors have gained importance for enhancing productivity, lowering costs, and improving worker safety. Sensors are devices that detect changes in the environment condition and act accordingly. They detect specific types of conditions (such as light, heat, sound, distance, pressure, presence or absence of gas/liquid, etc.) in the physical world and then generate a signal (usually an electrical signal) as a measure of their magnitude. Sensors commonly used in IoT systems include: Temperature sensors\nPressure sensor\nMotion detection sensors\nGas sensor\nProximity sensor\nIR sensors\nSmoke Sensor, etc. Temperature sensors Pressure sensor Motion detection sensors Gas sensor Proximity sensor IR sensors Smoke Sensor, etc.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What are different layers of the IoT protocol stack? Write the classification of IoT protocols.",
        "answer": "Internet of Things (IoT) protocols are ways of protecting data and ensuring it is exchanged securely between devices via the Internet. IoT protocols define how data is transmitted across the internet. By doing so, they ensure that data being exchanged between connected IoT devices is secure.   Classification of IoT Protocols- Classification of IoT Protocols Layer Protocol\nApplication layer\nAdvanced Message Queuing Protocol (AMQP)\nMessage Queue Telemetry Transport (MQTT)\nConstrained Application Protocol (CoAP)\nTransport layer\nUser Datagram Protocol (UDP)\nTransmission Control Protocol (TCP)\nNetwork layer\n6LoWPAN\nIP\nDatalink layer\nLPWAN\nIEEE 802.15.4 MAC\nPhysical layer\nIEEE 802.15.4 MAC\nNear field communication (NFC)\nRadio frequency identification (RFID)\nBluetooth Low Energy (BLE)\nEthernet Layer Protocol\nApplication layer\nAdvanced Message Queuing Protocol (AMQP)\nMessage Queue Telemetry Transport (MQTT)\nConstrained Application Protocol (CoAP)\nTransport layer\nUser Datagram Protocol (UDP)\nTransmission Control Protocol (TCP)\nNetwork layer\n6LoWPAN\nIP\nDatalink layer\nLPWAN\nIEEE 802.15.4 MAC\nPhysical layer\nIEEE 802.15.4 MAC\nNear field communication (NFC)\nRadio frequency identification (RFID)\nBluetooth Low Energy (BLE)\nEthernet Layer Protocol Layer Protocol Layer Protocol Application layer\nAdvanced Message Queuing Protocol (AMQP)\nMessage Queue Telemetry Transport (MQTT)\nConstrained Application Protocol (CoAP)\nTransport layer\nUser Datagram Protocol (UDP)\nTransmission Control Protocol (TCP)\nNetwork layer\n6LoWPAN\nIP\nDatalink layer\nLPWAN\nIEEE 802.15.4 MAC\nPhysical layer\nIEEE 802.15.4 MAC\nNear field communication (NFC)\nRadio frequency identification (RFID)\nBluetooth Low Energy (BLE)\nEthernet Application layer\nAdvanced Message Queuing Protocol (AMQP)\nMessage Queue Telemetry Transport (MQTT)\nConstrained Application Protocol (CoAP) Application layer Advanced Message Queuing Protocol (AMQP)\nMessage Queue Telemetry Transport (MQTT)\nConstrained Application Protocol (CoAP) Advanced Message Queuing Protocol (AMQP)\nMessage Queue Telemetry Transport (MQTT)\nConstrained Application Protocol (CoAP) Advanced Message Queuing Protocol (AMQP) Message Queue Telemetry Transport (MQTT) Constrained Application Protocol (CoAP) Transport layer\nUser Datagram Protocol (UDP)\nTransmission Control Protocol (TCP) Transport layer User Datagram Protocol (UDP)\nTransmission Control Protocol (TCP) User Datagram Protocol (UDP)\nTransmission Control Protocol (TCP) User Datagram Protocol (UDP) Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) Network layer\n6LoWPAN\nIP Network layer 6LoWPAN\nIP 6LoWPAN\nIP 6LoWPAN IP Datalink layer\nLPWAN\nIEEE 802.15.4 MAC Datalink layer LPWAN\nIEEE 802.15.4 MAC LPWAN\nIEEE 802.15.4 MAC LPWAN IEEE 802.15.4 MAC Physical layer\nIEEE 802.15.4 MAC\nNear field communication (NFC)\nRadio frequency identification (RFID)\nBluetooth Low Energy (BLE)\nEthernet Physical layer IEEE 802.15.4 MAC\nNear field communication (NFC)\nRadio frequency identification (RFID)\nBluetooth Low Energy (BLE)\nEthernet IEEE 802.15.4 MAC\nNear field communication (NFC)\nRadio frequency identification (RFID)\nBluetooth Low Energy (BLE)\nEthernet IEEE 802.15.4 MAC Near field communication (NFC) Radio frequency identification (RFID) Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE) Ethernet",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What are different communication models in IoT?",
        "answer": "In general, the Internet of Things is about connecting devices to the Internet, but how they connect is not always obvious. IoT devices connect and communicate through their technical communication models. An effective communication model shows how the process works and helps one understand how communication can be done. The Internet of Things (IoT) enables people and things (devices) to be connected wherever they are, using any network or service they like. Types of communication models - Request-Response Model: This communication model is based on the client (IoT Device) making requests and the server responding to those requests. Upon receiving a request, the server decides what response to provide, fetches the requested data, prepares the response, and then sends it back to the client. This model is stateless because the data between requests is not retained, therefore each request is handled independently. Request-Response Model: This communication model is based on the client (IoT Device) making requests and the server responding to those requests. Upon receiving a request, the server decides what response to provide, fetches the requested data, prepares the response, and then sends it back to the client. This model is stateless because the data between requests is not retained, therefore each request is handled independently. Request-Response Model:   Publisher-Subscriber Model: Publishers, brokers, and consumers are all involved in this communication model. Publishes are the sources of data that send data to topics. The broker manages the topics, and consumers (consume data from topics) subscribe to the topics. Publishers and consumers are unaware of each other. Upon receiving data for a topic from the publisher, the broker forwards it to all subscribed consumers. As a result, brokers are responsible for receiving data from publishers and sending it to the appropriate consumers. Publisher-Subscriber Model: Publishers, brokers, and consumers are all involved in this communication model. Publishes are the sources of data that send data to topics. The broker manages the topics, and consumers (consume data from topics) subscribe to the topics. Publishers and consumers are unaware of each other. Upon receiving data for a topic from the publisher, the broker forwards it to all subscribed consumers. As a result, brokers are responsible for receiving data from publishers and sending it to the appropriate consumers. Publisher-Subscriber Model:   Push-Pull Model: This communication model entails data producers pushing the data into queues, while data consumers pull the data from the queues. Neither producer nor consumer needs to know about each other. The queues help decouple the messages between the consumers and the producers. Also, queues act as a buffer when there is a mismatch between the rate at which producers push data and the rate at which consumers pull it. Push-Pull Model: This communication model entails data producers pushing the data into queues, while data consumers pull the data from the queues. Neither producer nor consumer needs to know about each other. The queues help decouple the messages between the consumers and the producers. Also, queues act as a buffer when there is a mismatch between the rate at which producers push data and the rate at which consumers pull it. Push-Pull Model:   Exclusive-Pair Model: Exclusive pairs are full-duplex, bidirectional communication models developed for constant/continuous connections between a client and server. After a connection is established, clients and servers can exchange messages. As long as a client doesn't send a request to close the connection, the connection remains open. The server is aware of every open connection. Exclusive-Pair Model: Exclusive pairs are full-duplex, bidirectional communication models developed for constant/continuous connections between a client and server. After a connection is established, clients and servers can exchange messages. As long as a client doesn't send a request to close the connection, the connection remains open. The server is aware of every open connection. Exclusive-Pair Model:  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. Write some of the most common IoT applications.",
        "answer": "Following are some of the most common real-world applications of IoT: Smart Homes: Smart homes are one of the most practical applications of IoT. Though IoT is applied in smart homes at various levels, the best one combines intelligent systems and entertainment. Example: Set-top box that allows you to record shows from remote, an automatic lighting system, a smart lock, etc.\nConnect Health: Connected health systems allow for real-time monitoring and patient care. Patient data assists in better medical decisions. Also, IoT improves the power, precision, and availability of current devices.\nWearables: Wearable devices have emerged as one of the earliest industries to deploy the IoT at scale. Various wearable devices are available today, such as Fit Bits, heart rate monitors, and smartwatches.\nConnected Cars: Connected cars use internet connectivity and onboard sensors to optimize their operation, maintenance, and passengers' comfort. Some of the leading automakers are working on bringing the next revolution to the car industry, including Tesla, BMW, Apple, and Google.\nHospitality: By applying IoT to the hotel industry, a higher level of service quality is achieved. Various interactions can be automated by using electronic keys that are sent directly to the mobile devices of guests. Therefore, the IoT technology enables integrated applications to manage activities such as tracking guests' locations, sending offers or information about interesting activities, placing orders for room service or room orders, and automatically charging the room account.\nFarming: A variety of tools are being developed to deal with Drip Irrigation, understanding crop patterns, Water Distribution, drones for farm surveillance, etc. Farmers will be able to increase yields and address concerns using these methods. Smart Homes: Smart homes are one of the most practical applications of IoT. Though IoT is applied in smart homes at various levels, the best one combines intelligent systems and entertainment. Example: Set-top box that allows you to record shows from remote, an automatic lighting system, a smart lock, etc. Smart Homes: Connect Health: Connected health systems allow for real-time monitoring and patient care. Patient data assists in better medical decisions. Also, IoT improves the power, precision, and availability of current devices. Connect Health: Wearables: Wearable devices have emerged as one of the earliest industries to deploy the IoT at scale. Various wearable devices are available today, such as Fit Bits, heart rate monitors, and smartwatches. Wearables: Connected Cars: Connected cars use internet connectivity and onboard sensors to optimize their operation, maintenance, and passengers' comfort. Some of the leading automakers are working on bringing the next revolution to the car industry, including Tesla, BMW, Apple, and Google. Connected Cars: Hospitality: By applying IoT to the hotel industry, a higher level of service quality is achieved. Various interactions can be automated by using electronic keys that are sent directly to the mobile devices of guests. Therefore, the IoT technology enables integrated applications to manage activities such as tracking guests' locations, sending offers or information about interesting activities, placing orders for room service or room orders, and automatically charging the room account. Hospitality: Farming: A variety of tools are being developed to deal with Drip Irrigation, understanding crop patterns, Water Distribution, drones for farm surveillance, etc. Farmers will be able to increase yields and address concerns using these methods. Farming:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. Explain how IoT works.",
        "answer": "Artificial Intelligence is at the core of IoT devices. The IoT consists of multiple components: sensors, a cloud component, data processing software, and cutting-edge user interfaces. IoT systems consist of sensors/devices connected to the cloud via some form of connectivity. A Raspberry Pi equipped with a quadcore processor can be used as an \"Internet gateway\" for IoT devices. It is a card-sized computer using which you can control outputs with GIPO (general purpose input/output) pins as well as collect data about real-world conditions using sensors. A sensor gathers live data from the surrounding environment and sent to a cloud infrastructure. Once the data reaches the cloud, the software can process it and decide what action to take, such as sending an alert or automatically adjusting the sensors/devices without user intervention. A user interface is used if user input is required or if they want to check in on the system. Adjustments made by the user are then sent inversely through the system - from the user interface to the cloud, and from the cloud back to the sensors/devices to make changes. As a result, a highly reactive and intuitive device is created which greatly increases automation.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. Explain the characteristics of IoT.",
        "answer": "The following are the most important features of IoT on which it operates:   Connectivity: Connectivity is the most important aspect of IoT. The IoT ecosystem (i.e. sensors, compute engines, data hubs, etc.) cannot operate properly without seamless communication among the interrelated components or objects. There are many ways to connect IoT devices including radio waves, Bluetooth, Wi-Fi, and Li-Fi.\nAnalyzing/Sensing: Once all the relevant things are connected, the next step is to analyze data that is being collected and use it to build effective business intelligence. It is very important to extract knowledge from the generated data. A sensor, for example, generates data, but those data won't be of much use unless they are interpreted properly by us.\nActive Engagements: A lot of today's interactions with connected technology occur via passive engagement. Through IoT, multiple products, cross-platform technologies, and services work together on an active engagement basis. The use of cloud computing in blockchain enables active engagements among IoT components in general.\nScalability: Each day, more and more elements are connecting to the IoT zone. IoT setups should therefore be able to handle massive expansion. The data generated as a result is immense, and it should be handled correctly.\nArtificial Intelligence: The IoT essentially makes things such as mobile phones, wearables, vehicles, etc., smart and enhances life by making use of data collection, artificial intelligence algorithms, and networked technologies. For example, if you have a coffee machine whose beans are going to end, it will order coffee beans from the retailer of your choice. Connectivity: Connectivity is the most important aspect of IoT. The IoT ecosystem (i.e. sensors, compute engines, data hubs, etc.) cannot operate properly without seamless communication among the interrelated components or objects. There are many ways to connect IoT devices including radio waves, Bluetooth, Wi-Fi, and Li-Fi. Connectivity: Analyzing/Sensing: Once all the relevant things are connected, the next step is to analyze data that is being collected and use it to build effective business intelligence. It is very important to extract knowledge from the generated data. A sensor, for example, generates data, but those data won't be of much use unless they are interpreted properly by us. Analyzing/Sensing: Active Engagements: A lot of today's interactions with connected technology occur via passive engagement. Through IoT, multiple products, cross-platform technologies, and services work together on an active engagement basis. The use of cloud computing in blockchain enables active engagements among IoT components in general. Active Engagements: Scalability: Each day, more and more elements are connecting to the IoT zone. IoT setups should therefore be able to handle massive expansion. The data generated as a result is immense, and it should be handled correctly. Scalability: Artificial Intelligence: The IoT essentially makes things such as mobile phones, wearables, vehicles, etc., smart and enhances life by making use of data collection, artificial intelligence algorithms, and networked technologies. For example, if you have a coffee machine whose beans are going to end, it will order coffee beans from the retailer of your choice. Artificial Intelligence:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. What is a thermocouple sensor?",
        "answer": "A thermocouple is a sensor that measures temperature by coupling two metal pieces together. The temperature is measured at a junction between these two pieces of metal which are joined at one end. A small voltage is generated by the metal conductors, which can be interpreted to calculate the temperature. A thermocouple is a simple, robust, and cost-effective temperature sensor available in multiple types and sizes. Additionally, they measure a wide temperature range, making them suitable for a variety of applications, such as scientific research, industrial settings, home appliances, and so on.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. Explain the term ‘smart city’ in IoT.",
        "answer": "IoT technology has been a driving force behind the development of smart cities since their inception. IoT technology will continue to grow as more countries adopt next-generation connectivity, and it will have a greater impact on our lives.  Connected sensors, lights, and meters are some of the IoT devices in smart cities that collect and analyze data. As a result, cities use this data to improve infrastructure, utilities, and other city services.   It is possible to create clever energy grids, automated waste management systems, smart homes, advanced security systems, traffic management mechanisms, water conservation mechanisms, smart lighting, and more with the help of the IoT. IoT has added a new layer of artificial intelligence and innovation to public utilities and urban planning, allowing them to be highly intuitive. These innovations have led to the emergence of smart homes and cities.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. What do you mean by PWM (Pulse Width Modulation)?",
        "answer": "Have trouble adjusting the brightness of the LEDs in your project? Changing the voltage of the power supply directly in the circuit isn't easy. In that case, you can use Pulse Width Modulation (PWM). Pulse Width Modulation (PWM), also referred to as PDM (Pulse Duration Modulation) refers to changing the amount of power that is delivered to a device. PWM is a technique for generating an analog signal from a digital source and is an efficient way to control the amount of energy delivered to a load without wasting any energy. PWM regulates voltage and is therefore used to control brightness in Smart Lighting Systems and also to control motor speed.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. Explain Shodan.",
        "answer": "Shodan (Sentient Hyper-Optimized Data Access Network) is a search engine similar to Google, but it does not search for websites, but rather maps and information about internet-connected devices/systems. Shodan is sometimes referred to as an IoT search engine. To put it simply, Shodan is an IoT tool used to identify Internet-connected devices. It keeps track of all the machines with direct Internet access. Cybersecurity experts use Shodan as a tool to protect individuals, companies, and even public utilities against cyber-attacks. Shodan lets you search for any internet-connected device, and it will tell you if it is publicly available or not.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. What do you mean by IoT Contiki?",
        "answer": "Contiki is an operating system developed for IoT devices with limited memory, power, bandwidth, and processing power. Despite being minimalist, it still contains many of the features common to modern operating systems. Programs, processes, resources, memory, and communication can be managed with its help. Due to its lightweight (by modern standards), mature, and flexible nature, it has become a go-to operating system by many academics, researchers, and professionals.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. Name some of the most suitable databases for IoT.",
        "answer": "The following databases are suitable for IoT: InfluxDB\nApache Cassandra\nRethinkDB\nMongoDB\nSqlite InfluxDB Apache Cassandra RethinkDB MongoDB Sqlite",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. Explain sharding.",
        "answer": "Sharding is the process of splitting very large databases into smaller, faster, and easier to manage pieces, called data shards. A shard is a small portion or chunk of a large data set. The principle of sharding is to split a logical dataset into multiple databases in order to store it more efficiently. In the case of a dataset that cannot be stored in a single database, sharding is necessary.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. What do you mean by Raspberry Pi?",
        "answer": "Raspberry Pi is a card-sized computer with features like General Purpose Input Output (GPIO) pins, WiFi, and Bluetooth that allow it to communicate, control, and connect to other external devices. Combining IoT applications with Raspberry Pi helps businesses embrace technology more effectively.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. State the difference between IoT and M2M.",
        "answer": "IoT (Internet of Things): It is referred to as a network comprised of interconnected physical objects that are capable of collecting and exchanging data. These devices contain embedded systems (software, electronics, networks, and sensors) that are able to collect data about the surrounding environment, transmit data over a network, respond to remote commands, or take actions based on data collected. The Internet of Things (IoT) is a subset of M2M (Machine to Machine) technology. In IoT, two machines communicate without human intervention, making it a part of M2M. IoT (Internet of Things): M2M (Machine to Machine): In M2M, devices communicate with each other directly via wired or wireless channels, without any human interaction. It enables devices to communicate and share data with each other without relying on the internet. Several applications of M2M communications are available, including security, tracking, and tracing, manufacturing, and facility management. M2M (Machine to Machine): IoT M2M\nIt is a network of connected devices (via the Internet) that have the ability to collect, process, and transmit data automatically without human intervention.    It allows two or more machines to communicate directly and perform certain tasks without requiring human intervention.  \nIn addition, IoT enables objects to interact with the internal and/or external environments, thereby influencing their decision-making. The M2M model exhibits some degree of intelligence. Devices capture data and share it with other connected devices, forming an intelligent network.\nIt facilitates cloud-based communication.    End-to-end communication between devices/machines is supported.  \nIn order to improve the end-user experience, data is shared between other applications.   Only parties communicating with each other have access to the data. \nInternet access is usually required for devices to communicate and share data.    Devices don't usually require an Internet connection for communication.  \nMany machines are able to communicate over the internet.   The communication between machines is limited to one at a time.   \nOpen API integrations are supported.  Open API integrations are not supported.  \nA number of Internet protocols are used, including HTTP, FTP, and Telnet.  Communication technologies and traditional protocols are used. IoT M2M\nIt is a network of connected devices (via the Internet) that have the ability to collect, process, and transmit data automatically without human intervention.    It allows two or more machines to communicate directly and perform certain tasks without requiring human intervention.  \nIn addition, IoT enables objects to interact with the internal and/or external environments, thereby influencing their decision-making. The M2M model exhibits some degree of intelligence. Devices capture data and share it with other connected devices, forming an intelligent network.\nIt facilitates cloud-based communication.    End-to-end communication between devices/machines is supported.  \nIn order to improve the end-user experience, data is shared between other applications.   Only parties communicating with each other have access to the data. \nInternet access is usually required for devices to communicate and share data.    Devices don't usually require an Internet connection for communication.  \nMany machines are able to communicate over the internet.   The communication between machines is limited to one at a time.   \nOpen API integrations are supported.  Open API integrations are not supported.  \nA number of Internet protocols are used, including HTTP, FTP, and Telnet.  Communication technologies and traditional protocols are used. IoT M2M IoT M2M IoT M2M It is a network of connected devices (via the Internet) that have the ability to collect, process, and transmit data automatically without human intervention.    It allows two or more machines to communicate directly and perform certain tasks without requiring human intervention.  \nIn addition, IoT enables objects to interact with the internal and/or external environments, thereby influencing their decision-making. The M2M model exhibits some degree of intelligence. Devices capture data and share it with other connected devices, forming an intelligent network.\nIt facilitates cloud-based communication.    End-to-end communication between devices/machines is supported.  \nIn order to improve the end-user experience, data is shared between other applications.   Only parties communicating with each other have access to the data. \nInternet access is usually required for devices to communicate and share data.    Devices don't usually require an Internet connection for communication.  \nMany machines are able to communicate over the internet.   The communication between machines is limited to one at a time.   \nOpen API integrations are supported.  Open API integrations are not supported.  \nA number of Internet protocols are used, including HTTP, FTP, and Telnet.  Communication technologies and traditional protocols are used. It is a network of connected devices (via the Internet) that have the ability to collect, process, and transmit data automatically without human intervention.    It allows two or more machines to communicate directly and perform certain tasks without requiring human intervention. It is a network of connected devices (via the Internet) that have the ability to collect, process, and transmit data automatically without human intervention. It allows two or more machines to communicate directly and perform certain tasks without requiring human intervention. In addition, IoT enables objects to interact with the internal and/or external environments, thereby influencing their decision-making. The M2M model exhibits some degree of intelligence. Devices capture data and share it with other connected devices, forming an intelligent network. In addition, IoT enables objects to interact with the internal and/or external environments, thereby influencing their decision-making. The M2M model exhibits some degree of intelligence. Devices capture data and share it with other connected devices, forming an intelligent network. It facilitates cloud-based communication.    End-to-end communication between devices/machines is supported. It facilitates cloud-based communication. End-to-end communication between devices/machines is supported. In order to improve the end-user experience, data is shared between other applications.   Only parties communicating with each other have access to the data. In order to improve the end-user experience, data is shared between other applications. Only parties communicating with each other have access to the data. Internet access is usually required for devices to communicate and share data.    Devices don't usually require an Internet connection for communication. Internet access is usually required for devices to communicate and share data. Devices don't usually require an Internet connection for communication. Many machines are able to communicate over the internet.   The communication between machines is limited to one at a time. Many machines are able to communicate over the internet. The communication between machines is limited to one at a time. Open API integrations are supported.  Open API integrations are not supported. Open API integrations are supported. Open API integrations are not supported. A number of Internet protocols are used, including HTTP, FTP, and Telnet.  Communication technologies and traditional protocols are used. A number of Internet protocols are used, including HTTP, FTP, and Telnet. Communication technologies and traditional protocols are used.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What do you mean by IoT Gateway? What is the role of a gateway in IoT?",
        "answer": "Devices such as IoT gateways enable communication between IoT devices, sensors, equipment, and systems. Basically, an IoT gateway is a central hub for all IoT devices. It connects the IoT devices to each other and to the cloud, converting communication among the devices and analyzing data to create useful information. Several critical functions are performed by an IoT gateway, including translating protocols, encrypting, processing, managing, and filtering data. As part of an IoT ecosystem, gateways sit between devices and sensors to communicate with the cloud.   IoT gateways are commonly used for the following purposes: Interconnecting devices\nConnecting devices to the cloud\nTransforming IoT communications\nData filtering\nReducing security risks, etc. Interconnecting devices Connecting devices to the cloud Transforming IoT communications Data filtering Reducing security risks, etc.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. Explain WoT (Web of Things).",
        "answer": "WoT (Web of Things) is an advancement of the Internet of Things by integrating smart things not only with the Internet (network) but with the Web Architecture (application). In short, the Web of Things (WoT) is aimed at facilitating the interoperability and usability of IoT.  It is a web standard for enabling communication between smart devices and web applications.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What do you mean by MQTT (Message Queue Telemetry Transport Protocol)?",
        "answer": "The Message Queuing Telemetry Transport protocol (MQTT) is a publish/subscribe message protocol designed for networks with limited bandwidth and IoT devices with extremely high latency (delay in data transmission). This messaging protocol is simple and lightweight, suited to devices and networks with low bandwidth, high latency, or insecure networks. It has been designed to reduce network bandwidth and resource requirements of devices and to ensure supply security. Furthermore, these principles are beneficial for IoT or M2M devices, since battery life and bandwidth are very important. Because MQTT is efficient and lightweight, it can be used to monitor or control a large amount of data. Nowadays, MQTT is used in a variety of industries, including automotive, manufacturing, telephony, oil and gas.   Publishes are the sources of data that send data to topics. The broker manages the topics, and consumers subscribe to the topics. Upon receiving data for a topic from the publisher, the broker forwards it to all subscribed consumers. As a result, brokers are responsible for receiving data from publishers and sending it to the appropriate consumers.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. Explain Bluegiga APX4 protocol.",
        "answer": "The Bluegiga APx4 is a low power wireless System-on-Module (SOM). It's an ideal development platform for developing gateways since it's equipped with integrated Wi-Fi, Bluetooth 4.0, ARM, and Linux. Wireless and Bluetooth low energy (BLE) can be used together without interference as they are compliant with coexistence protocols. Bluegiga Apx4 supports both Wi-Fi and Bluetooth, and its 450mhz Arm9 processor provides smooth performance.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What is IoT device management and why do we need it?",
        "answer": "Once installed, IoT devices may need to be updated or timely fixed. Occasionally, it must be replaced or repaired, resulting in downtime. The problem can be solved using IoT Device management, which can keep the devices in good shape. IoT device management involves provisioning, authenticating, configuring, monitoring, provisioning, and maintaining the connected devices and software's. Effective device management is vital for ensuring the health, security, and connectivity of IoT devices.  In order to manage IoT devices, you need to meet the following four requirements.   Provisioning and Authentication: IoT devices can be attacked quite easily since their network can be accessed via the Internet. This problem is solved by provisioning and authenticating the devices. By provisioning, you modify the device from its off-the-shelf settings to those needed for it to work with your network. In order to prevent intrusions and safeguard proprietary information, authentication ensures only authorized devices are enrolled.\nConfiguration and Control: It is always necessary to configure a new device before you can begin using it. It is also critical to control and configure devices after deployment to ensure certain aspects such as performance, security, and functionality. Implementing control capability will be easier this way.\nMonitoring and Diagnostics: The device may go down for a time when there are software bugs or certain other issues. To diagnose these issues, users must constantly monitor their devices. Device management assists in diagnosing these issues in order to resolve them quickly and efficiently.\nUpdates and Maintenance: For a device to function flawlessly, it must be updated after it has been installed. This may involve adding new features. Good device management hinges on the ability to update and maintain the software of remote devices securely. Provisioning and Authentication: IoT devices can be attacked quite easily since their network can be accessed via the Internet. This problem is solved by provisioning and authenticating the devices. By provisioning, you modify the device from its off-the-shelf settings to those needed for it to work with your network. In order to prevent intrusions and safeguard proprietary information, authentication ensures only authorized devices are enrolled. Provisioning and Authentication: Configuration and Control: It is always necessary to configure a new device before you can begin using it. It is also critical to control and configure devices after deployment to ensure certain aspects such as performance, security, and functionality. Implementing control capability will be easier this way. Configuration and Control: Monitoring and Diagnostics: The device may go down for a time when there are software bugs or certain other issues. To diagnose these issues, users must constantly monitor their devices. Device management assists in diagnosing these issues in order to resolve them quickly and efficiently. Monitoring and Diagnostics: Updates and Maintenance: For a device to function flawlessly, it must be updated after it has been installed. This may involve adding new features. Good device management hinges on the ability to update and maintain the software of remote devices securely. Updates and Maintenance:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. State the difference between IoT and IIoT.",
        "answer": "IoT (Internet of Things): Any device that can connect to the internet and transfer data to a remote data server is termed the Internet of Things (IoT). IoT (Internet of Things): IIoT (Industrial Internet of Things): In the case of IoT devices used for industrial purposes, these devices are referred to as Industrial Internet of Things (IIoT). IIoT is the subset of IoT. IIoT (Industrial Internet of Things): Difference between IIoT and IoT- Difference between IIoT and IoT- IIoT IoT\nIt supports industrial-oriented applications such as manufacturing, power plants, oil & gas, etc.  It supports customer-oriented applications such as wearables to robots and machines. \nThe focus is on large scale networks.   The focus is on small scale networks. \nBoth wired and wireless communication methods are utilized.  Typically, wireless communication methods are utilized. \nA large amount of data is handled.  It can handle data ranging from medium to high. \nThis is a B2B (business-to-business) and is designed to increase efficiency and safety at production facilities.  This is B2C (business-to-consumer) and is designed to make the lives of consumers more convenient. IIoT IoT\nIt supports industrial-oriented applications such as manufacturing, power plants, oil & gas, etc.  It supports customer-oriented applications such as wearables to robots and machines. \nThe focus is on large scale networks.   The focus is on small scale networks. \nBoth wired and wireless communication methods are utilized.  Typically, wireless communication methods are utilized. \nA large amount of data is handled.  It can handle data ranging from medium to high. \nThis is a B2B (business-to-business) and is designed to increase efficiency and safety at production facilities.  This is B2C (business-to-consumer) and is designed to make the lives of consumers more convenient. IIoT IoT IIoT IoT IIoT IoT It supports industrial-oriented applications such as manufacturing, power plants, oil & gas, etc.  It supports customer-oriented applications such as wearables to robots and machines. \nThe focus is on large scale networks.   The focus is on small scale networks. \nBoth wired and wireless communication methods are utilized.  Typically, wireless communication methods are utilized. \nA large amount of data is handled.  It can handle data ranging from medium to high. \nThis is a B2B (business-to-business) and is designed to increase efficiency and safety at production facilities.  This is B2C (business-to-consumer) and is designed to make the lives of consumers more convenient. It supports industrial-oriented applications such as manufacturing, power plants, oil & gas, etc.  It supports customer-oriented applications such as wearables to robots and machines. It supports industrial-oriented applications such as manufacturing, power plants, oil & gas, etc. It supports customer-oriented applications such as wearables to robots and machines. The focus is on large scale networks.   The focus is on small scale networks. The focus is on large scale networks. The focus is on small scale networks. Both wired and wireless communication methods are utilized.  Typically, wireless communication methods are utilized. Both wired and wireless communication methods are utilized. Typically, wireless communication methods are utilized. A large amount of data is handled.  It can handle data ranging from medium to high. A large amount of data is handled. It can handle data ranging from medium to high. This is a B2B (business-to-business) and is designed to increase efficiency and safety at production facilities.  This is B2C (business-to-consumer) and is designed to make the lives of consumers more convenient. This is a B2B (business-to-business) and is designed to increase efficiency and safety at production facilities. This is B2C (business-to-consumer) and is designed to make the lives of consumers more convenient.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. Explain the meaning of Arduino.",
        "answer": "Arduino is an open-source platform for building electronics projects using easy-to-use hardware and software. A microcontroller is the common feature of all Arduino boards. The microcontrollers on board are capable of reading inputs (e.g., light on a sensor, an object near a sensor) and converting them to outputs (drive a motor, ring an alarm, turn on an LED, display information on an LCD). It is possible to connect multiple devices and exchange data in real-time between them. It is also possible to monitor them remotely using a simple interface.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. Explain sketch in Arduino and how will you reduce the size of sketch.",
        "answer": "Arduino refers to a program as a sketch. In other words, it is a bit of code that is uploaded to and executed on an Arduino board. It is possible to reduce the size of the sketch by removing unnecessary libraries from the code and making it simple and short.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. What is GPIO (General Purpose Input/Output)?",
        "answer": "GPIO (General-purpose input/output) is a standard interface using which Raspberry Pi and other microcontrollers can connect to external electronic components/devices. These are basically programmable pins on an integrated circuit or board that allow digital input or output signals to be controlled programmatically.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. State different between Arduino and Raspberry Pi.",
        "answer": "We can use many different kinds of controller boards for our hardware projects. Arduino and Raspberry Pi are among the most popular. Difference between Arduino and Raspberry Pi- Arduino Raspberry Pi\nArduino is an open-source, programmable USB microcontroller.  It is a microprocessor-based minicomputer (SBC).  \nArduino boards have a microcontroller that includes a CPU, RAM, and ROM. The Arduino Board has additional hardware for power supply, programming, and IO (Input/Output) connectivity.    The Raspberry Pi SBC (Single board computer) comes with everything you need to run a computer, from a processor, memory, storage, graphics driver, to connectors.  \nWith Arduino, you can interface sensors and control LEDs and motors.  It works well for developing Python-based applications.   \nIt has a simple hardware and software architecture.   On the other hand, Raspberry Pi boards have a complex architecture.  \nIt is possible to build your own Arduino board using the open-source hardware and software files of Arduino.   Since the Raspberry Pi is not open-source, it cannot be used for this purpose.   \nIt is used to run one single task at a time.  It can perform several tasks at once such as running software, web browsing, doing programming, etc.. Arduino Raspberry Pi\nArduino is an open-source, programmable USB microcontroller.  It is a microprocessor-based minicomputer (SBC).  \nArduino boards have a microcontroller that includes a CPU, RAM, and ROM. The Arduino Board has additional hardware for power supply, programming, and IO (Input/Output) connectivity.    The Raspberry Pi SBC (Single board computer) comes with everything you need to run a computer, from a processor, memory, storage, graphics driver, to connectors.  \nWith Arduino, you can interface sensors and control LEDs and motors.  It works well for developing Python-based applications.   \nIt has a simple hardware and software architecture.   On the other hand, Raspberry Pi boards have a complex architecture.  \nIt is possible to build your own Arduino board using the open-source hardware and software files of Arduino.   Since the Raspberry Pi is not open-source, it cannot be used for this purpose.   \nIt is used to run one single task at a time.  It can perform several tasks at once such as running software, web browsing, doing programming, etc.. Arduino Raspberry Pi Arduino Raspberry Pi Arduino Raspberry Pi Arduino is an open-source, programmable USB microcontroller.  It is a microprocessor-based minicomputer (SBC).  \nArduino boards have a microcontroller that includes a CPU, RAM, and ROM. The Arduino Board has additional hardware for power supply, programming, and IO (Input/Output) connectivity.    The Raspberry Pi SBC (Single board computer) comes with everything you need to run a computer, from a processor, memory, storage, graphics driver, to connectors.  \nWith Arduino, you can interface sensors and control LEDs and motors.  It works well for developing Python-based applications.   \nIt has a simple hardware and software architecture.   On the other hand, Raspberry Pi boards have a complex architecture.  \nIt is possible to build your own Arduino board using the open-source hardware and software files of Arduino.   Since the Raspberry Pi is not open-source, it cannot be used for this purpose.   \nIt is used to run one single task at a time.  It can perform several tasks at once such as running software, web browsing, doing programming, etc.. Arduino is an open-source, programmable USB microcontroller.  It is a microprocessor-based minicomputer (SBC). Arduino is an open-source, programmable USB microcontroller. It is a microprocessor-based minicomputer (SBC). Arduino boards have a microcontroller that includes a CPU, RAM, and ROM. The Arduino Board has additional hardware for power supply, programming, and IO (Input/Output) connectivity.    The Raspberry Pi SBC (Single board computer) comes with everything you need to run a computer, from a processor, memory, storage, graphics driver, to connectors. Arduino boards have a microcontroller that includes a CPU, RAM, and ROM. The Arduino Board has additional hardware for power supply, programming, and IO (Input/Output) connectivity. The Raspberry Pi SBC (Single board computer) comes with everything you need to run a computer, from a processor, memory, storage, graphics driver, to connectors. With Arduino, you can interface sensors and control LEDs and motors.  It works well for developing Python-based applications. With Arduino, you can interface sensors and control LEDs and motors. It works well for developing Python-based applications. It has a simple hardware and software architecture.   On the other hand, Raspberry Pi boards have a complex architecture. It has a simple hardware and software architecture. On the other hand, Raspberry Pi boards have a complex architecture. It is possible to build your own Arduino board using the open-source hardware and software files of Arduino.   Since the Raspberry Pi is not open-source, it cannot be used for this purpose. It is possible to build your own Arduino board using the open-source hardware and software files of Arduino. Since the Raspberry Pi is not open-source, it cannot be used for this purpose. It is used to run one single task at a time.  It can perform several tasks at once such as running software, web browsing, doing programming, etc.. It is used to run one single task at a time. It can perform several tasks at once such as running software, web browsing, doing programming, etc..",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. State difference between IoT and WSN (Wireless Sensor Network)?",
        "answer": "WSN (Wireless sensor network): It uses a network of dedicated sensors to monitor and record the physical conditions of the environment and to organize the recorded data at one central location. WSN: Sensor nodes connected without a wire to gather data. WSN (Wireless sensor network): IoT (Internet of Things): It is referred to as a network comprised of interconnected physical objects that are capable of collecting and exchanging data. These devices contain embedded systems (software, electronics, networks, and sensors) that are able to collect data about the surrounding environment, transmit data over a network, respond to remote commands, or take actions based on data collected. IoT: WSN + Any physical object (Thing) + IP address + Internet + App + Cloud computing + etc.… IoT (Internet of Things)",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. Explain IoT GE-PREDIX.",
        "answer": "GE (General Electric) Predix is a software platform for collecting industrial instrument data. This platform enables industrial-grade analytics for operations optimization and performance management via a cloud-based PaaS (platform as a service).",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. Name some of the wearable Arduino Boards.",
        "answer": "The following wearable Arduino boards are available: Lilypad Arduino main board\nLilypad Arduino simple\nLilypad Arduino simple snap\nLilypad Arduino USB Lilypad Arduino main board Lilypad Arduino simple Lilypad Arduino simple snap Lilypad Arduino USB",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. Explain IoT asset tracking.",
        "answer": "\"Asset tracking\" entails tracking a particular asset and its location, whether it's a hammer, an X-ray machine, a vehicle, a shipping crate, or even a person. How does the IoT fit in here? Rather than manually tracking assets like a supervisor filling out a form when the asset arrives at a specific location, IoT tracking systems use sensors and asset management software to track things automatically. The assets are fitted with sensors, which broadcast their location over the internet on a continuous or periodic basis, and the software displays this information for you to see. Different types of IoT asset tracking systems transmit location information differently, such as via GPS, Wi-Fi, or cellular networks.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. What do you mean by “Thingful”?",
        "answer": "Thingful is a search engine for the internet of things (IoT). Using millions of publicly available IoT data resources, it provides a geographical index of real-time data from connected devices around the globe. With Thingful, IoT managers can detect patterns, identify anomalies, and analyze trends to solve problems. Conclusion A wide range of organizations can benefit from the internet of things. A key objective of the Internet of Things is to extend internet access from smartphones, laptops, and tablet devices to relatively basic devices such as toasters. As the Internet of Things has grown, there have been more opportunities in the fields of Mobile development, Cars, and household products that utilize and connect the Internet. With IoT technology pervading every aspect of our lives, an increased need for professionals trained to handle IoT devices has developed. Hence, if you're considering an IoT interview, you've found the right place. In this article, we have compiled a list of the most frequently asked IoT interview questions with answers curated for both freshers and experienced professionals. Hopefully, these IoT interview questions will help you succeed in your next interview. Wishing you continued success. Useful Resources: Useful Resources: Azure Interview Azure Interview AWS Interview AWS Interview Networking Interview Networking Interview Difference Between IoT and M2M Difference Between IoT and M2M IoT Applications IoT Applications Top Features of IoT Top Features of IoT IoT Projects IoT Projects Highest Paying Jobs In India Highest Paying Jobs In India",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "1) What is IoT? / What is the Internet of Things?",
        "answer": "IoT is an acronym that stands for Internet of Things. Kevin Ashton first coined the term IoT or the Internet of Things in 1999. It is a network setup of physical objects referred to as \"things\" embedded with software, electronics, network, and sensors that allow these objects to communicate by collecting and exchanging data over a WIFI network without human interaction. The IoT devices include embedded systems, i.e., software, electronics, networks, and sensors that allow them to collect data about the surrounding environment, transmit data over a network, respond to remote commands, or take actions based on data collected.\nSome examples of IoT devices or things available today are wearables, implants, smartphones, vehicles, machinery, appliances, computing systems, or other devices that can send and receive data.\nThe main goal of IoT is to extend internet connectivity from standard devices like computers, mobile, tablets and enable internet connectivity to non-communicable devices such as AC, washing machine, toaster, fan, cooler, and other household items.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "2) What are the most important characteristics or features of IoT?",
        "answer": "Following is a list of the most important characteristics or features of IoT:\n\nADVERTISEMENT\nConnectivity for communication: Connectivity is the most important part of IoT. The Internet of Things consists of networks, data hubs, sensors, etc., for connectivity and cannot work properly without seamless communication among the interrelated components or objects. There are many ways to connect IoT devices such as radio waves, Bluetooth, WiFi, Li-Fi, etc.\nAnalyzing/Sensing: Analyzing or sensing comes into play when all the relevant components or objects are connected. This step is used to analyze collected data and use it to build effective business intelligence. It is very important to extract knowledge from the collected data. For example, the collected data by sensor won't be of much use unless it is interpreted properly.\nScalability: Scalability is used to handle the massive data generated by the sensors. Each day, more and more elements connect to the IoT zone, generating massive data. So, scalability is a must to handle the immense data correctly.\nActive Engagements: IoT uses multiple products, cross-platform technologies, and services to work together on an active engagement basis. It uses blockchain cloud computing to enable active engagements among IoT components in general.\nArtificial Intelligence: Artificial Intelligence is an essential part of IoT to make things such as mobile phones, wearables, vehicles, household devices, etc. to make them working smart. For this purpose, it uses data collection, artificial intelligence algorithms, and networked technologies. For example, if you are using an IoT-based coffee machine, it will order coffee beans from the retailer of your choice if the coffee beans will end.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "3) How does the IoT (Internet of Things) affect our everyday lives?",
        "answer": "IoT can make smart devices for our everyday lives. The devices embedded in IoT technology can manifest a greater quantum of automation than those available before. IoT can create a greater network that enables different devices to interact freely with each other and make our everyday lives better.\nIoT has a lot of positive effects on our daily life. For example, the IoT-enabled sensor-driven home appliances such as refrigerators automatically turn off when not in use or virtual assistants, which can regulate most of our devices from the lights used in our room to our television, air condition, or playing our favorite music, etc.\nIoT is not only limited to our gadgets. Even our wearables have evolved a lot with the use of IoT. Our smartwatches, sunglasses, earphones, and many more have the mark of IoT. If we talk about large-scale applications, the transportation industry, the government infrastructure, and educational initiatives are also hugely affected by IoT technology. According to a report by Garter, by 2020, approximately 20.6 billion devices will have IoT elements that connect them.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "4) What industries can be benefitted from IoT?",
        "answer": "A wide range of industries can be benefitted from IoT. Some of them are as follows:\nConsumer devices\nHealthcare\nAgriculture\nManufacturing\nAutomation and public transportation\nUtilities and energy\nSmart cities and smart homes\nEnvironmental benefits etc.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "5) What are the different types of components used in IoT?",
        "answer": "There are usually four main components used in IoT devices:\n\nSensors: Sensors are the most important part of IoT devices. In IoT devices, a sensor is used as an input device to gather live data from the surrounding environment. It can gather different types of data. For example, your phone has a temperature sensor, a GPS, an accelerometer, or a live video feature on a social media platform. Sensors make it possible for IoT devices to connect to the real world and outside the environment. This is all possible because of sensors.\nConnectivity Mediums: After gathering data from the sensors, all data is sent to a cloud infrastructure. This is possible because of connecting the sensors to the cloud using a variety of communication mediums such as mobile or satellite networks, Bluetooth, WI-FI, WAN, etc. There are various types of IoT devices, and they use different types of connectivity mediums for communication.\nData Processing: Data Processing: The data processing compound comes into play when the data has been collected and has reached the cloud. Now, it is the responsibility of the data processors to process the data for further use. Data processing software is required to enhance IoT devices in several ways. For example, it can adjust the air conditioner's temperature or recognize the faces on mobile phones and so on.\nUser Interface: The IoT devices require a user interface to interact with a user. A user interface is the visible, tangible component of an IoT system that users can access. It makes the information presentable and valuable for the end-user. A well-designed user interface can enrich the experience for users and encourage them to interact more. It makes the information easy and accessible to end-users, like sending alerts via notification, email, or text message.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "6) What is Raspberry Pi?",
        "answer": "The Raspberry Pi is a small-sized (a credit card sized), low-cost computer that can be plugged into a computer monitor or TV and used with a standard keyboard and mouse. It can do all the operations like a conventional computer. It provides additional features such as onboard WIFI, GPIO pins, and Bluetooth to communicate with external electronic devices.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "7) What are the key advantages of IoT?",
        "answer": "IoT devices are a complete package of advanced automation and analytics system that makes use of networking, big data, sensing, and Artificial Intelligence to provide a complete solution.\nFollowing are the key advantages or benefits of IoT:\n\nBetter customer experience: IoT devices provide a better customer experience by automating tasks. For example, an IoT-enabled electronic device automatically detects any issue by its sensors and can notify its user.\nEase of Access: IoT devices use sensors to access real-time information from any location or environment. It just requires a smart device connected to the internet.\nTechnical optimization: IoT devices use improved technology, making them more efficient. It can make even old \"dumb\" devices into \"smart\" ones by making them capable of transmitting data over the internet and facilitating communication with people and other IoT-enabled devices. For example, washing machines, coffee machines, smart toys, smart microwaves can act smart with IoT.\nEfficient Resource Management: Usually, we rely on superficial insights to make decisions, but IoT devices provide real-time insights that facilitate us to do efficient resource management.\nEffective Time Management: This is one of the biggest advantages of IoT. It can save a lot of time. For example, you can operate your household devices at your fingertip. While commuting to work, you can read the latest news on your phones, online shopping, browse a blog about your favorite hobby, etc.\nImproved security: IoT provides additional security to organizations and individuals as they can access and lock their things on their phones. For example, by using IoT technology in surveillance, we can increase an organization's security standards and identify any suspicious activity on our phones.\n\nCreate new business opportunities: IoT devices can create new business insights and generate new opportunities and reduce operational costs.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "8) What are the different types of sensors used in IoT?",
        "answer": "Sensors are the most important components used in IoT devices. Sensors are important because they are the input devices that detect changes in the environment condition and act accordingly. In the physical world, sensors are used to detect specific conditions such as heat, light, sound, distance, pressure, presence or absence of gas/liquid, etc., and then generate an electrical signal after measuring their magnitude. In recent years, IoT sensors have evolved in a great way to enhance productivity, lowering costs, and improve worker safety.\nFollowing are the most commonly used sensors in IoT systems:\nIR sensors\nMotion detection sensors\nTemperature sensors\nPressure sensor\nGas sensor\nProximity sensor\nSmoke Sensor, etc.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "9) What are the biggest challenges or risks associated with IoT?",
        "answer": "Following is the list of biggest challenges or security risks associated with IoT:\n\n\nPrivacy: With IoT devices, you will always be concerned regarding data security and privacy. IoT devices are a setup of many connected devices vulnerable to hacking. Many IoT devices collect and transmit personal data over an open network without encryption that may be easy for hackers to access. Hackers may also use cloud endpoints to attack servers.\nReliability: IoT devices have a highly distributed nature. That's why it is difficult to ensure the reliability of IoT systems. Several conditions can affect the components of IoT systems, such as natural disasters, disruptions in cloud services, power outages, and system failures.\n\nNetwork Connectivity and Control: Network connectivity is a must for IoT devices, but sometimes, it may be challenging, particularly if the connected devices are widely dispersed in remote locations or if bandwidth is severely limited.\nConstant and Continuous Power Supply: IoT devices require a constant and continuous power supply to act properly. It may not be easy in some cases.\nInsufficient testing and updating: The market of IoT is very new and fast-paced. Many companies or manufacturers rush to start releasing their products and software without doing enough testing and proper updating. Many of them don't provide timely updates, leaving them vulnerable to data theft. IoT devices should be tested thoroughly and updated as soon as new vulnerabilities are identified to maintain security and win customers' trust.\nLack of knowledge and awareness: IoT is a very new and growing technology, so; people do not have proper knowledge or awareness about these devices. It may also act as a security threat to users' confidentiality.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "10) What is PWM or Pulse Width Modulation?",
        "answer": "PWM is an acronym that stands for Pulse Width Modulation. It is an analog signal that varies the amount of time when the signal is high. The signal can be high or low, and the user can modify the time proportion.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "11) What are the different layers of the IoT protocol stack, and why are they used?",
        "answer": "IoT protocols are the ways to protect data and ensure it to be exchanged securely between devices via the Internet. IoT protocols define how data is transmitted across the Internet and ensure that the data exchanged between connected IoT devices is secure anyway.\nDifferent communication layers and their respective IoT protocols:\nLayer IoT Protocol\nPhysical layer\nIEEE 802.15.4 MAC\nNear field communication (NFC)\nRadiofrequency identification (RFID)\nBluetooth Low Energy (BLE)\nEthernet\nDatalink layer\nLPWAN\nIEEE 802.15.4 MAC\nNetwork layer\n6LoWPAN\nIP\nTransport layer\nUser Datagram Protocol (UDP)\nTransmission Control Protocol (TCP)\nApplication layer\nAdvanced Message Queuing Protocol (AMQP)\nMessage Queue Telemetry Transport (MQTT)\nConstrained Application Protocol (CoAP)",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "12) What are the key differences between IoT and IIoT?",
        "answer": "The key differences between IoT and IIoT are as follow:\nIoT IIoT\nIoT is an acronym that stands for Internet of Things. IIoT is also an acronym that stands for Industrial Internet of Things.\nIoT is generally used in home appliances and devices. So, its service model is human-centric. IIoT is generally used in industry for industrial purposes. So, its service model is machine-centric.\nIoT is used in customer-oriented applications. IIoT is used in industry-oriented applications.\nIt uses wireless devices for communication transportation. It uses both wired and wireless devices for communication transportation.\nThe quality of data in IoT is medium to high. The quality of data in IIoT is high to very high.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "13) What is Arduino used in IoT?",
        "answer": "Arduino is a free electronics platform that provides easy-to-use hardware and software. It is used in IoT as it has a microcontroller that reads input from the sensors and controls the device according to the written program.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "14) What are the different types of communication models used in IoT?",
        "answer": "IoT devices must be connected to the internet to work properly. These devices connect and communicate through their technical communication models. There are several ways to connect them to the internet for communication. An effective communication model is required for proper communication. Following is a list of different types of communication models used in IoT:\nRequest-Response Communication Model\n\nAs the name specifies, the request-response communication model is based on the client making requests and the server responding to those requests. When the server receives a request, it decides what response to be provided. It fetches the requested data, prepares the response, and then sends it back to the client. This model does not retain the data between requests; therefore, each request is handled independently. That's why this is called a stateless model.\nPublisher-Subscriber Communication Model\n\nIn this communication model, publishers, brokers, and consumers are all involved in communication. Publishes are used as sources of data that send data to topics. The broker manages the topics, and consumers subscribe to the topics. Publishers and consumers are not directly related to each other. When the publisher receives the data for a topic, the broker forwards it to all subscribed consumers. It means brokers are responsible for receiving data from publishers and sending it to the appropriate consumers.\nPush-Pull Communication Model\n\nThe push-pull communication model ensures that data producers push the data into queues while consumers pull the data from the queues. In this communication model, neither producer nor consumer knows about each other, and it is the responsibility of the queue to decouple the messages between the consumers and the producers. Here, queues also act as a buffer if any mismatch is found between the rate at which producers push data and the rate at which consumers receive it.\nExclusive-Pair Model\n\nThis is the most efficient model for quick communication. This is a full-duplex, bidirectional communication model developed for constant/continuous connections between a client and server. Once a connection is established, the clients and the servers can send and receive messages. As long as a client doesn't send a request to close the connection, the connection remains open. The server takes care of every open connection.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "15) What is the basic difference between an IoT device and a normal sensor device?",
        "answer": "A normal sensor device does not need an active internet connection to work properly. On the other hand, IoT devices always require an active internet connection to work properly.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "16) What is the Bluegiga APX4 protocol?",
        "answer": "The Bluegiga APX4 protocol is a solution based on a 450MHz ARM9 processor. It is used for communication in IoT devices as it supports both the WIFI and BLE platform.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "17) What are some of the most common real-world applications of IoT?",
        "answer": "IoT can solve many real-life problems. Following is a list of some most common real-world applications of IoT:\nSmart Homes: The most common and practical real-life application of IoT is smart homes. We can apply IoT in smart homes at various levels, but intelligent systems and entertainment are the best and most common use. For example, smart door lock, automatic lighting system, automatic air-conditioning, and smart set-top box facilitate you to record shows from anywhere, etc.\nWearable devices: Wearable devices are also great examples of IoT. Nowadays, the young generation uses many IoT-enabled wearable devices like Fit Bits, heart rate monitors, smartwatches, etc. This field has emerged as a very profitable business industry.\nConnected Health System: Connected health systems can be used to monitor critical patients. IoT can also improve the power, precision, and availability of current devices used in the medical field. It provides real-time monitoring and patient care to be used in better medical decisions.\nInternet-Connected Vehicles: Internet-connected vehicles use internet connectivity and onboard sensors to provide better operation, maintenance, and comfort to the passengers. The leading automobile companies like Tesla, BMW, Apple, and Google are working on IoT to revolutionize the automobile industry.\nAgriculture and Farming: IoT can also be very useful in agriculture and farming. Using IoT, we can develop tools for drip irrigation, understanding the crop patterns, water distribution, drones for farm surveillance, etc. Farmers can increase the yields by using IoT tools and methods.\nHotels and Hospitality Industry: IoT can provide higher service quality to the hotel and hospitality industry. IoT-enabled integrated applications can manage several activities such as tracking guests' locations, sending them attractive offers, placing orders for room service, automatically charging the room account, etc. Using IoT, we can automate many things in hotels and achieve a higher level of service quality.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "18) Explain the working of IoT?",
        "answer": "IoT is based on Artificial Intelligence. The basic technology used in IoT devices is Artificial Intelligence. IoT contains multiple components like sensors, cloud components, data processing software, cutting-edge user interfaces, etc. In IoT systems, sensors connect the devices to the cloud. It uses Raspberry Pi equipped with a quad-core processor used as an \"Internet gateway\" for IoT devices.\nRaspberry Pi is a card-sized computer that controls outputs with GIPO (general purpose input/output) pins. It collects data about real-world conditions using sensors. Sensors collect live data from the surrounding environment and send it to a cloud infrastructure. When the cloud receives the data, the software can process it and decide what action to take, such as sending an alert or automatically adjusting the sensors/devices without user intervention.\nA user interface is required to check if user input is required or if they want to check in on the system. The user's adjustments are then sent inversely through the system to the cloud and from the cloud back to the sensors/devices to make changes. As a result, it thoroughly creates a highly reactive and intuitive device which increases the automation of the device.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "19) Why is PWM used in IoT?",
        "answer": "PWM stands for Pulse Width Modulation. In IoT, Pulse Width Modulation is mainly used to control the speed of the DC motor, control the direction of a servo motor, dim the LED, etc.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "20) What are the various wireless communications boards available in Raspberry Pi?",
        "answer": "There are mainly two wireless communications boards available in Raspberry Pi:\nWiFi\nBLE/Bluetooth",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "21) What do you understand by the thermocouple sensor?",
        "answer": "A thermocouple sensor is a specific type of sensor used to measure temperature by coupling two metal pieces together. These two pieces of metal are joined at one end, and the temperature is measured at a junction. A small voltage is generated by the metal conductors, which is interpreted to calculate the temperature. A thermocouple is a simple, robust, and economical temperature sensing device available in multiple types and sizes. The thermocouple sensor can measure a wide temperature range, which makes it suitable for various applications, such as scientific research, industrial settings, home appliances, etc.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "22) What functions are used to read analog and digital data from a sensor in Arduino?",
        "answer": "There are two functions used to read analog and digital data from a sensor in Arduino:\ndigitalRead()\ndigitalWrite()",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "23) What is Shodan in IoT?",
        "answer": "Shodan is an acronym for Sentient Hyper-Optimized Data Access Network. Like Google, it is a search engine, but it does not search for websites. Instead, Shodan is an IoT search engine used for mapping and providing information about internet-connected devices/systems.\nIn other words, we can say that Shodan is an IoT tool used to identify Internet-connected devices and keep tracking of all the machines with direct Internet access. Cybersecurity experts use the Shodan tool to protect individuals, companies, and public utilities against cyber-attacks. On Shodan, you can search for any internet-connected device and check if it is publicly available or not.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "24) What are the different available models in Raspberry Pi used in IoT?",
        "answer": "The different available models in Raspberry Pi used in IoT are:\nRaspberry Pi 1 Model A\nRaspberry Pi 1model A+\nRaspberry Pi 1 Model B\nRaspberry Pi 1 Model B+\nRaspberry Pi Zero\nRaspberry Pi 3 Model B\nRaspberry Pi Zero W\nRaspberry Pi 2",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "25) What are some most suitable databases for IoT?",
        "answer": "Following is a list of some most suitable databases for IoT:\nInfluxDB\nMongoDB\nApache Cassandra\nRethinkDB\nSqlite",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "26) What is MicroPython?",
        "answer": "MicroPython is a Python implementation with a small subset of its standard library. We can optimize and run it on the ModeMCU microcontroller.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    },
    {
        "question": "27) What do you understand by sharding?",
        "answer": "Sharding is the process of splitting a huge database into smaller, faster, and manageable pieces, called data shards. A shard is a small part of a large data set. Sharding is mainly used to split a logical dataset into multiple databases to make them store more efficiently. It is necessary in the case of a dataset that cannot be stored in a single database.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "iot"
    }
]